Benjamin Asabir

1588 South Parade Court, Mississauga, ON, L5M6E7 Cell: 647 649 2192 Email: benasabir@gmail.com

Profile

Experienced Visual Merchandiser and Marketer with a demonstrated history of working in the retail industry. Skilled in merchandising, sales, event management, art direction and much more. Graduated with honours and now a professional with a Diploma focused on merchandising and marketing

Education

Humber College - Diploma in Fashion Arts and Business

Experience

HUDSONS BAY

VISUAL MERCHANDISING / MARKETING

(AUG 2013 - PRESENT)

- Create excitement and the optimal customer experience through Special Events set-up
- Execute National and Regional ISM (In store marketing) programs in a timely manner.
- Actively participate in training programs and work with multiple retail vendors to ensure their brands are updated and up to company standards.
- Meet with department managers and discuss strategies to improve sales.
- Responsible for execution of window set-ups, prop production is, mannequins and styling.
- Execute floor plans and implement visual presentation strategy to positively impact store sales.
- Execute marketing objectives i.e. Event set-up, Shop set-up and Seasonal set-up.
- Maintain cleanliness and organization in areas assigned.
- Create visual impact with mannequins, floor displays and merchandise presentation that enhance the Company's image as a fashion store and entice the customer to buy through the execution of Company Visual Presentation / Marketing directions and guidelines.

OLD NAVY

MERCHANDISING

(FEB 2012 - FEB 2013)

- Read Plano-gram and moved a specific type of merchandise to a different section.
- Processed shipment every week, replenished all floors when necessary.
- Dressed up mannequins according to the directions of Head Office.
- Arranged back-stock room by style number and size and effectively maneuver between sales floor and stock room.
- Demonstrated appropriate selling behaviours to achieve selling and non-selling KPI's (key performance indicators) to deliver business objectives.
- Steamed merchandise and carefully hung or folded them to create appealing layout

Benjamin Asabir

1588 South Parade Court, Mississauga, ON, L5M6E7 Cell: 647 649 2192 Email: benasabir@gmail.com

Experience

HARRY ROSEN

STOCK MANAGER

(MAY 2011 - DEC 2011)

- Conducted a floor check daily to make sure all merchandise was hanging/folded properly.
- Received new shipment every morning and placed it on sales floor, folded all merchandise neatly.
- Price and security tagged all merchandise that goes out on the sales floor.
- Accurately priced all merchandise and stayed late nights to do markdowns/markups.
- Trained new stock employees.
- Organized workload for in-store marketing team, stock team and interns to complete tasks efficiently and neatly.

HOLT RENFREW

VISUAL MERCHANISER (INTERN)

(AUG 2010 - DEC 2010)

- Worked on making props for window display, remodelled old props by reshaping, painting etc.
- Assisted in setting up the store according to promotions or events taking place (Easter, Halloween, Christmas etc).
- Ensured that orders for display materials and supplies were placed in a timely manner.
- Worked on exciting window displays several times a week to capture customers' attention.
- Arranged and kept back-stock/ visual room clean and tidy.
- Accountable for the care and maintenance of display materials and fixtures.

Achievements

- Certificate in extensive use of Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook, Publisher).
- Completion of Red cross training.
- Certificate Of Recognition at Hudsons Bay
- Backstage dresser for Toronto Mercedes Benz Fashion Week 2015, 2016
- Part of team to build and install very first Visual Merchandising Display Window at Humber College Lakeshore Campus.